第三季
第九集
童
话
镇
《童话镇》前情提要
Previously on "Once upon a time"...
你为了那把匕首的魔力  放弃了比尔菲
You traded Baelfire for the power of a dagger,
而我拿你换取了青春
and I traded you for youth.
我不是当父亲的料
I was never meant to be a father.
潘时日无多了
Pan's dying.
他需要用至诚之心
He needs the heart of the truest believer.
这是交换  亨利得死
It's a trade. Henry will die.
你不是碰巧找到亨利的  对吗
Your finding Henry wasn't an accident, was it?
不明白你在说什么
Whatever do you mean?
你从哪找到他的
Where did you get him?
咒语都可以被打破
All curses can be broken.
他们的孩子就是解咒的关键
Their child is the key.
强大的力量需要足够的牺牲
Great power requires great sacrifice.
告诉我什么样的心脏能达到要求
Tell me, what will suffice?
你最珍爱的东西的
The heart of the thing you love most.
诅咒来了
The curse! It's here!
我在等着呢
I'm waiting!
怎么这么久才来  宝贝儿
What took you so long, dearie?
你知道原因的
You know what took so long.
是啊  诅咒
Oh, yes. The curse.
你做到了
You did it.
对
That's right.
我做到了
I did it.
而我想告诉你
And I wanted you to know it.
免得你忘记一切
Before you, like all the pathetic denizens
就像这片悲惨土地上的可怜居民一样
of this wretched land, forgets everything.
你感觉怎么样
How did it feel?
看见咒语生效吗
Watching the curse cloud form?
感觉像是胜利
Felt like victory.
杀了你最爱的人
How did it feel
感觉怎么样
to kill the thing you love most?
取出你父亲的心脏
Ripping the heart out of your father.
感觉怎么样
How did that feel?
这是诅咒的代价
It was the price of the curse.
我的感受并不重要
How it felt doesn't matter.
他会明白的
He would've understood.
我夺回了属于我的生活
I took my life back.
我必须这样
I had to.
我赢了
I won.
但你来了这里  来幸灾乐祸了
And yet, here you are, feeling the need to gloat.
少了点什么  对吧  宝贝儿
Something's missing, isn't it, dearie?
才没有
Not at all.
我拥有想要的一切
I have everything I want.
没有什么能阻止我了
Nothing can stop me now.
并非如此
Not quite.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
救世主
The savior.
白雪公主和白马王子的孩子
The child of Snow White and Prince Charming.
她能阻止你
She can stop you.
她能打破诅咒
She can break the curse.
看来除掉一个孩子
Well, it looks like getting rid of a baby
列入了我的任务清单
just made my to-do list.
当然啦
Of course it did.
但就算你成功了
But even if you succeed with that,
你还有一个更大的问题
you have an even bigger problem.
你的内心有个洞
Now there's a hole... in your heart.
有一天
And someday,
你会找我来填满它的
you will come to me to fill it.
你高估了你预见的能力
You overestimate your powers of foresight.
你低估了你做的事需要的代价
And you underestimate the price of what you've done!
*你会看见  你会来找我*
*You shall see, you will come to me
*你还需要更多*
*There is more you need, oh!*
嘲弄我对你没好处的
Your taunts will get you nowhere.
我太了解你了
I know you too well.
你想做另一笔交易
You wanna make another deal.
我不想
Well, I won't.
交易
A deal?
你已答应我  让我在这片新土地过上安逸的生活
You've already promised me a good life in this new land.
我还会向你要求什么呢
What more can I want from you?
离开这牢笼
Oh, to be... let out of this cage?
取消我们最后一次交易
To... be let out of our last deal?
逃脱诅咒
To escape the curse?
我为什么要那样呢  宝贝儿
But why would I desire that, dearie?
我就想待在这里
I'm exactly where I want to be.
天啊  他昏迷了吗
Oh, god. Is he unconscious?
亨利  能听见我们吗
Henry, can you hear us?
他的心脏到了潘身上  就昏迷了
He passed out as soon as his heart went into Pan.
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
撑住  孩子
Just hang in there, buddy.
你对他做了什么
What the hell'd you do to him?
我什么也没做  艾玛
Oh, I didn't do anything, Emma.
是亨利
It was Henry.
他自愿把心脏给我的
He offered me his heart of his own free will.
我要夺回来
I'm gonna take it back from you.
我觉得你没这种能力
I don't think you have it in you.
朗普斯金就没有
Rumplestiltskin didn't.
你怎么会有呢
Why should you?
他在哪里
Where is he?
-你做了什么  -他在这个盒子里
- What did you do? - Why, he's right in this box,
完整无损  也不会碍事了
safe and sound and out of the way.
不幸的是  他没法再伤害我了
Unfortunately for you, he can't hurt me anymore.
你也不能
And neither can you.
真的吗
Really?
你觉得怎么样
How did that feel?
你在挠我痒痒吧
Like a tickle.
他怎么样
How is he?
你会没事的  亨利
You're gonna be all right, Henry.
我们会带你回家的
We're gonna get you home.
十一年前
你想见我吗
You, um, you wanted to see me?
没错
Yes, I did.
如果是关于鹏哥的养狗证的事
All right, well, if this is about Pongo's dog license,
应该还在办理
I-I believe it's still up-to-date.
跟你的狗无关
This has nothing to do with your dog.
镇长女士  你没事吧
Madame mayor, are you all right?
我很好
I'm okay.
恕我直言  你看起来并不好
Excuse me for saying so, but you don't seem okay.
我无法忍受你说话这么直
I don't tolerate that sort of bluntness.
我可是皇...
I'm the q--
镇长
The mayor.
而我是治疗师
And I'm a therapist.
所以你才叫我来  对吧
That's--that's why you asked me here, isn't it?
什么事困扰你  感觉如何
What's bothering you? What are you feeling?
感觉不到
Nothing.
我什么都感觉不到
I'm feeling nothing.
这么说的话
If I were to guess, I would say that...
我觉得你是个要强的女人
you're a driven woman,
有时会让你内心留下空洞
and sometimes that can leave a hole.
留下什么
A what?
空洞  即空虚
A hole. An emptiness.
生活中不仅仅只有工作
There's more to life than work.
也许这才是你不满的原因
And maybe that's why you feel dissatisfied.
我没有不满
I'm not dissatisfied.
我爱我的生活
I love my life.
但没人与你分享还有什么意义
Well, what's the point if you've got no one to share it with?
你又太直白了
There's that bluntness again.
生命中有没有那么一刻
Has there ever been a time in your life
你没有这种感觉
when you haven't felt this way?
那个小男孩来的时候
When that little boy visited.
欧文
Owen.
是孩子
A child.
让你生活更有意义
That can provide so much meaning.
我需要一个孩子  戈登  还需要你帮忙
I need a child, Gold. And I need your help.
我很荣幸  但不感兴趣
Well, I'm flattered, but uninterested.
不是要杀了他
Not like that.
我一上午都在咨询领养站
I spent all morning talking to adoption agencies.
候选名单都排到两年后了
The wait-lists are over two years long.
但你  戈登
But you, Gold,
你知道如何打破陈规
you know how to cut through red tape.
如果有人能钻政策的空子
And if anyone can work the system
帮我领养个孩子  那人就是你
and find me a baby, it's you.
你想领养吗
You wish to adopt?
这有什么稀奇的
Well, don't look so surprised.
不稀奇
Oh, I'm not.
你肯定能成为
I'm sure you'll make a...
一位"好"母亲
well, a mother of some sort.
到底能不能帮忙
Can you help me?
当然可以
Of course I can.
但听我一言
But a word of caution--
问问你自己  你准备好领养孩子了吗
Ask yourself, is this something you're ready for?
不用准备好  我就是需要
It's something I need.
这完全是两码事
Well, that may not be the same thing.
我会帮你弄到孩子
I'll get you a child.
但孩子能否让你好过点
But whether or not that's helping you,
我们拭目以待
remains to be seen.
成了父母  一切都要以孩子为先
When you become a parent, you must put your child first.
无论发生什么
No matter what.
这保护咒
This preservation spell
能让他保持这个状态更久一点
can keep him in this condition for a while longer.
为我们找到潘争取时间
Buy us time to get to Pan.
你也曾是迷失男孩  知道他会去哪吗
You were a lost boy. Any idea where he went?
我知道他住哪里
Well, I-I mean, I know where he lived,
在哪里收容迷失男孩
where--his compound.
白痴  你说的我们都知道
Well, that's idiotic. We all know that.
你不觉得他会蠢到回到那里吗
You think he's stupid enough to go back?
-你真没用  -够了
- You're useless. - Okay, enough.
别跟我说什么够了
Don't tell me what's enough.
我的孩子要死了
My son is dying!
是我们的孩子
Our son.
所以我懂你的感受
So yes, I know how you feel.
你根本不懂我的感受
You have no idea what I feel.
你有父母  有这个...
You have your parents. You have this...
人
person,
还有个海盗为你着迷
a pirate who pines for you.
你什么都有  还告诉我
You have everything, and yet you claim
你懂我的感受
to know what I feel?
我只有亨利
All I have is Henry,
我不能失去他  因为他是我的全部
and I am not about to lose him, because he is everything.
你说得没错
You're right.
我不懂你的感受
I don't know what you feel.
所以你想干什么
So what do you wanna do?
你喜欢操控一切  现在来啊
You wanna the run the show? Run it.
我们怎么救亨利
How do we save Henry?
我不知道
I don't know.
就算找到了潘  他之前就很强大
Even if we can find Pan, he was powerful before.
有了亨利的心
With Henry's heart,
我们根本奈何不了他
I-I don't know if we can hurt him.
当然可以
Yes, we can.
你们看
Look.
你割伤他了
You nicked him.
他能流血  我们就能伤他
If he can bleed, we can hurt him.
能伤他就能杀他
And if we can hurt him, we can kill him.
一定要杀了他
And we will.
戈登在盒子里吗
Gold is in a box?
那戴维就永远都不能离开梦幻岛了
Then David can never leave the island.
玛丽·玛格丽特  这不重要
Mary Margaret, that doesn't matter.
我们已经说好了
I've already made peace with that.
重要是救活亨利
What matters is Henry.
我们有多少时间
How much time do we have?
保护咒也许只能撑一小时
Maybe an hour before the preservation spell wears off.
如果他会飞
If he's airborne,
他可能在岛上任何一个角落
he could be anywhere on the island.
一个小时不够
An hour isn't much time.
我建议现在就开始找
I suggest we get started looking.
他在哪里
Where is he?
走了
Gone.
现在为时已晚  他赢了
There's nothing you can do. He's already won.
潘永远不会失败
Pan never fails.
你不愿意说是吗
You won't talk?
那我只好逼你说了
How 'bout I make you talk?
瑞金娜  等等
Regina, wait.
没时间了
There's no time!
我认为严刑拷问在这里并不是最佳上策
I don't think torture is our best move here.
瞧瞧那些孩子  他们已经在地狱里走了一遭
Look at these kids. They've been to hell and back.
我们需要想点别的办法
We need to try something else.
试试装可爱吧
Yeah, we tried the cute and cuddly.
他们不会对劝说有反应的
They don't respond to reason.
你还有什么提议
What else do you have to offer?
每个孩子最想要的
What every kid wants.
是妈妈
A mother.
有什么消息吗
You have news?
有  命运也许是站在你这边的
Yes. Fate may be on your side.
今天早上  我和一位机构人员谈过了
This morning I, uh, spoke with an agency
他把一个凤凰城的小男孩
who had placed a baby boy from Phoenix
安置在波士顿附近一户人家里
with a family nearby in Boston.
住在一户人家里吗  命运如何
With a family? How is that fate?
因为到最后一刻  领养手续未能成行
Because at the last minute, the adoption fell through.
这种事总是会发生的
It happens.
所以这小婴孩需要一个家
So the baby still needs a home.
没错
Indeed.
正如我所说  命运似乎是站在你这边的
As I said, fate appears to be on your side.
领养机构在波士顿
The agency is in Boston.
米尔斯女士
Well, Ms. Mills,
你的申请好得令人难以置信
your application is almost too good to be true.
我是说你的推荐信无可挑剔
I mean, your references are impeccable.
而且在你所居住的这个童话镇上
And this town you live in-- Storybrooke--
你是镇长吗
You're the mayor?
已经第三届了  所有人都同意
Third term. All unopposed.
从未听说过童话镇
Never heard of Storybrooke.
那是个世外桃源
Oh, it's a... hidden gem.
对孩子们来说是个和平  完美的地方
Peaceful, perfect for children.
就像童话故事里的那样
It's like a fairy tale.
如果你有时间  应该去瞧瞧
You should come visit sometime.
我每年只有两周的假期
I get two weeks off a year.
请恕我直言  山多士有全套自助假期
And all due respect, Sandals has an inclusive buffet.
童话镇也有山多士吗
You got that in Storybrooke?
还没有
I'm afraid not.
总而言之
Anyway,
我已经和你解释过你的权利和责任
I've explained your rights and responsibilities,
但是有一项我还要具体强调一下
but there's one item I'd like to go over in detail.
这是保密收养
This is a closed adoption,
也就是说你永远不可能
which means you'll never be able to contact
联系你孩子的亲生父母
your child's birth parents.
信息是完全封锁的  包括父母的姓名
It's a complete information blackout-- parents' names,
种族  家谱记录
ethnicity, genealogical records.
你不会得到任何有关的信息
You won't have access to any of it.
我只关心我孩子的未来
I'm concerned with my child's future,
不关心他的过去
not his past.
那么恭喜你  准备好见你的儿子了吗
Well, then congratulations. You ready to meet your son?
准备好了
Yes!
你好啊
Well, hello there.
是命运对吗
It was fate, wasn't it?
亨利
Henry.
亨利吗
Henry, huh?
现在很少有人给孩子起名叫亨利了
You don't meet a lot of Henrys nowadays.
非常古老的名字
Very old world.
这是我父亲的名字
It was my father's name.
他不久前过世了
He passed some time ago.
很遗憾
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
但愿他走得安详
I hope it was peaceful, at least.
需要帮忙吗
Oh, you need some help?
不用了  我行的
Oh, no, no. I've got it.
来吧  亨利
Come on, Henry.
我们回家咯
Let's go home.
孩子们  听我说
Guys, listen to me.
我们不会伤害你们的
We are not gonna hurt you.
我知道你们忠于潘  我明白
I know you're loyal to Pan, and I get that.
但是你们犯了一个严重的错误
But you are making a terrible mistake.
长时间以来
For a long time,
我也以为自己再也找不到家人
I thought I was never gonna find my family.
我曾经是个孤儿  就和你们大家一样
I was an orphan, like all of you.
一个迷失的女孩
A lost girl.
今天使我想起  我并不是孤身一人
And I was reminded today that I am not alone,
我有很多爱我的人
that I have a lot of people that love me.
而我从未想过这一切会发生
And I never thought that was gonna happen.
如果这些能发生在我身上  你们也可以的
If that can happen to me, it can happen to you.
潘是我们唯一需要的家人
Pan is the only family we need.
不  家人不会像他这么做
No. Family doesn't do what he did.
潘欺骗你们  让你们干坏事
Pan lied to you and made you do terrible things.
他骗了亨利  说服他
He lied to Henry, and convinced him
交出自己的心
to give up his own heart.
来拯救这座岛
To save the island.
不  是为了拯救他自己
No, to save himself.
不要听她说  潘关心我们所有的人
Don't listen to her. Pan cares about all of us.
不  他不关心
No, he doesn't.
我们关心你们
We care about you.
我们能救你们
And we can save you!
我们可以带你们一起回家
We can take you home with us to our land.
不必再害怕潘
There's no reason to fear Pan anymore.
直到他从亨利心脏吸取力量
Until he absorbs the power from Henry's heart,
就能阻止他了
he can be stopped.
你们只需要告诉我们他在哪
You just have to tell us where he is.
趁潘还让你们活着的时候  赶紧走吧
Leave now while Pan still allows you to breathe.
这是你唯一能得到的帮助
That's the only help you'll get.
潘...在哪儿
Where... is Pan?
不...告诉你
Not...telling.
你真的能带我们回家吗
Can you really bring us home?
闭上你的嘴
Shut your mouth!
是的
Yes.
在你们的帮助下
With your help.
他的思考树
His thinking tree.
-不  -是的  思考树
- No! - Yes, his thinking tree.
闭嘴  都闭嘴
Stop it! All of you!
那是什么地方
What is that?
他想一个人呆着的时候就去那儿
It's where he goes when he wants to be alone.
你们可以在那里找到他  不远
You can find him there. It's not far.
不  别相信她
No, don't trust her.
你能告诉我们在哪儿吗
Can you tell us where that is?
可以
Yeah.
但你要发誓
But you have to swear,
发誓你会带我们一起走
swear that you'll take us with you.
我保证
I promise.
我们就要回家了
We are going home.
我们所有人都是
All of us.
这个小淘气是谁啊
Who is this bundle of joy?
你对他哭很不满吗
Do you have a problem with him crying?
不  当然不
No, of course not.
好了  该安静安静了  该安静了
Okay, it's time to be quiet. It's time to be quiet.
怎么了
What?!
需要点建议吗
You want some advice?
讲个故事试试吧
Try a story.
他们就是这么安抚自己的
That's how they soothe themselves.
睡前故事  让他们适应你的声音
A bedtime story. Gets 'em used to your voice.
在鲁比身上就有效
Worked with Ruby.
她的问题出现地比较晚
Her issues started later.
没事  没事的
Hey. Okay. It's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
很久很久以前  有一个...
Once upon a time, there was--
他的心脏跟火车头一样有力
Well, his heart's as strong as a locomotive.
他的肺也很健康  很显然
And his lungs are healthy, clearly.
那需不需要做个血液检测
Well, what about a blood test?
或者胸透
Or a chest x-ray?
他吸烟吗
Is he a smoker?
什么
What?!
听着  问题很明显
Look, it's obvious what the problem is.
他就是个爱哭的孩子
He's a crying baby.
我付钱就让你干这个
I paid for this?
实际上  是你的保险付的钱
Actually, your insurance did.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
我可以开点药
I can prescribe you something.
十毫升母亲的关爱
10 ccs of maternal love.
威尔医生  没有人爱自己的孩子胜过我
Dr. Whale, no one loves their child more than me.
也就是说我的孩子有问题
Which means there's something wrong with my son.
你的工作就是帮助他
Your job is to help him.
你倒是帮啊
Do it!
当然  我可以让他做额外的检测
Sure, I could order additional testing,
但是  婴儿做会有风险
but, uh, with babies, there are risks.
一般来说都是没什么也不值得做
And it's generally nothing and not worth it.
一般来说
"Generally"?
有些时候  可能有不正常的东西
Well, in some cases, there could be something abnormal happening.
但那就需要找到亲生母亲才能知道
But we'd need the birth mother to find out.
你是说抛弃了他的那个女人
You mean the woman who abandoned him?
你觉得她能安抚他
You think she can soothe him?
我才是他的母亲
I'm his mother.
你误会我了  瑞金娜
You misunderstand me, Regina.
如果这个孩子真的有哪里不正常
If something were in fact wrong with the baby,
或许他妈妈的医疗档案里有记录
maybe there's something in her medical records,
一些能引起疾病的基因方面的问题
something genetic that could be causing a problem.
能帮我们填补空白的
But the only people who can help us fill those blanks
只有亲生父母
are the biological parents.
但这是保密收养
But it was a closed adoption.
没办法联系他们
There's no way to contact them.
西德尼  那笔记下来
Sidney, grab a pencil.
在波士顿达特茅斯街上有家收养机构
There's an adoption agency in Boston on Dartmouth Street.
再说一遍  有杂音
Say again? There's noise on the line.
布兰切特女士
Ms. Blanchard.
你好
Oh. Hi.
这是谁啊
Who's this?
是亨利
Meet Henry.
发挥点作用
Make yourself useful.
达特茅斯街上的波士顿天使收养机构
Boston Angels Adoption on Dartmouth.
我需要亨利亲生母亲的名字
I need the name of Henry's biological mother.
这不是违反法律的吗
Isn't that against the law?
所以我才给你打电话  西德尼
Well, that's why I called you, Sidney.
因为我知道  为了我你会不惜一切代价
Because I know, for me, you'll do whatever it takes.
我一定要知道
I need this done.
我的儿子出了些问题
There's something wrong with my son.
他不停地...
He won't stop c--
哭
crying.
去查吧
Just--just do it.
-你是怎么做到的  -做到什么
- How did you do that? - Do what?
让他停止哭泣
M-make him stop crying.
我只是抱着他  他真可爱
Well, I'm just holding him. He's so sweet.
不不不
No. Oh, no, no.
抱歉  我做错什么事了吗
I'm so sorry. I--did I do something?
没有
No.
不  你没有  是我的问题
No, you didn't. It's me.
精灵森林  在那儿吗
The pixie woods? That's where it is?
就在北边
It's just north of here.
以前精灵尘就是在那里生长的
It's where the pixie dust used to grow.
你知道在哪儿吗
Do you know where that is?
是的  现在那里全部都荒废了
Aye. The whole region is deserted now.
好几个世纪以来  只有潘去过
No one but Pan has set foot in those woods in centuries.
那我们就去创造历史吧
Then let's make history.
你得留在这儿
We're gonna need you here.
一旦拿回亨利的心脏  我们得立刻回程
Once we get Henry's heart, it's gonna be a race back.
两边都要有人
We need help on both ends.
好
Okay.
需要我们做什么
What do you need from us?
把这些迷失男孩都集中起来
Let's gather up the lost boys.
全部送上海盗船
Get 'em on board the "Jolly Roger."
准备好让船起飞
Prepare the ship to fly.
但愿你有马羽帆
Let's hope you have a pegasus sail.
不然就得指望风大得能把船吹起来吧
Otherwise, we're at the mercy of the trade winds.
潘的影子在我们手里  它能帮我们回家
Pan's shadow's in here. It'll get us home,
只要你的船不散架
Long as your ship holds together.
只要你的计划不出差错
Well, as long as your plan holds together,
我的船也没问题
she will.
我会时时刻刻守在亨利身边
Henry's gonna be with me the entire time.
你们俩去找潘的期间
Nothing is gonna happen to him
他绝对不会出事的
while you two are away.
是三个人
You mean three.
也许我的下半辈子
I may be trapped on this island
都得在这岛上度过了
for the rest of eternity.
所以我绝不会错过
So if you think I'm not going to
这段与女儿相处的最后时光
be spending my last moments with my daughter,
别傻了
you're crazy.
好  上路吧
Okay. Let's do it.
亨利
Henry...
亨利  求你告诉我你究竟想要什么
Henry, I promise if you just tell me what you want,
为了你我什么都愿意做  任何事
I'll do anything for you. Anything.
求你了
Please? Just...
给我个机会
give me a chance.
谢谢
Thank you.
西德尼
Sidney.
查出什么了
What'd you find?
收养所那边查不出什么
The agency was a dead end,
但我在卫生处那边想了点法子
but I worked my magic with the health department.
生母的资料全查出来了
Found out all about his mother.
我这就把信息传真给你
I'm faxing over the information right now.
-应该马上就能收到了  -来了
- You should have it any second. - It's here.
不
No.
你知道的
You knew.
知道什么
Knew what exactly?
这个你帮我从凤凰城找来的孩子
The child that you located for me in Phoenix,
他的生母是十八年前
his mother was found in the woods,
在童话镇外的树林里被发现的
outside of Storybrooke, 18 years ago.
还真是巧呢
What a startling coincidence.
十八年前
18 years ago?!
我真的不知道你在说什么
I fear I'm missing the significance.
请原谅
You'll have to forgive me.
我的记忆力现在不行了
My memory's not what it used to be.
亨利的母亲幼年时
Henry's mother was found
在某个重要的日子
as a baby,
被人发现
on a very significant day--
就是在那一天
the day this town...
童话镇
this town...
童话镇怎么了
This town what?
她就是关键  是不是
She's important, isn't she?
这位母亲
This mother.
她是否重要
Is she important?
当然了  她生下了你的儿子
I suppose inasmuch as she gave birth to your son.
是你
You.
这一切
You built this
全是你预谋好的  是不是
into this whole thing, didn't you?
你让我收养他  因为他的母亲
You made this happen because the mother,
她是...
she's...
她怎么了  镇长女士
She's what, madame mayor,
你好像很怕这位母亲
this mother that you seem to fear so much?
你真对我所说的一无所知吗
Oh, you really know nothing of what I'm talking about?
我知道你很不安  这点倒是显而易见的
Well, I know you're upset. That much is clear.
你说过  我会再来找你的
You told me I'd come to you,
你说  我的心上有一个空洞
that I'd have a hole in my heart.
你还说...
And...
你想终结这一切
You want this to end.
我辛辛苦苦打造的镇子
This town, what I built.
你想要引来孩子的生母  从而摧毁我的心血
You wanna destroy it all by bringing the mother back.
所以你谋划了这一切
That's why you did all this!
知道吗  你眼下有黑眼圈了
Do you know you have dark circles under your eyes
声音还发颤
And a weary tremble in your voice?
可怜人啊
Poor thing.
身为人母把你折磨成什么样了
Look what motherhood has done to you.
你就继续装傻吧  小魔鬼
Play dumb all you want, you little imp.
你该知道自己在和谁作对
You should know who you're dealing with by now.
我牺牲了一切才换来现在的生活
I sacrificed everything to build this life!
没有任何事物能阻挡我复仇的脚步
And nothing will tear me away from my revenge!
亨利明天就将被送回波士顿
Henry goes back to Boston tomorrow!
看啊
Look.
小心点
Careful.
潘不会无缘无故把盒子丢在这儿的
Pan wouldn't have just left it behind for no reason.
这是能让戴维回家的唯一希望了
It's David's only way home.
没有戈登  我们将被困在此地
Without Gold, we're stuck here.
玛丽·玛格丽特
Mary Margaret!
你们怎么还是这么蠢
Are you still at it?
你们就不明白吗
Don't you know?
彼得·潘永远不会失败
Peter Pan never fails.
没想到你们能找到我
I didn't expect you to find me.
不过话说回来  看到你们我一点都不吃惊
But then again, I shouldn't be surprised.
你们都是母亲
You're mothers.
非常在意自己的孩子
Quite tenacious about your offspring.
说来你们也许不信  但我明白那种感受
Believe it or not, I understand that.
但如果你们是为亨利而来的
But if you're looking to see Henry again,
我不得不告诉你们
I have to tell you,
你们母子相见的唯一办法
there's only one place you'll be reunited--
就是死亡
in death.
说明我都写好了
I wrote out instructions
关于他的睡觉  午睡和喂食
for his bedtime, nap time, and feeding.
米尔斯女士  我向你保证
Ms. Mills, I assure you,
宝宝会有专业人士照顾
the baby will be in expert hands here.
我知道
I know.
我只是很伤心我们处不来
I'm just sad that this couldn't work out.
事情总是...
The circumstances were...
难以预料
unforeseen.
不是每个孩子和父母都适合的
Not every child is the right fit for a parent.
有时领养孩子
And sometimes, putting the child first
首先代表有勇气放弃他
can mean having the strength to give him up.
亨利再去哪
Where will Henry go next?
已经有个家庭等着了
We already have a new family lined up.
他会好好的
He's gonna be just fine.
这样  你再和他待会
I tell you what. You take a minute.
我一会回来  好吗
I'll be right back. Okay?
亨利
Oh, Henry.
你值得比我更好的父母
You deserve better than me.
你真是所有人里
You truly are the only one in all the realms
唯一信任我的人
who believes in me.
你可以让我抱他
Would you like me to hold him
然后我们最后签字确认
so we can get the last little signature?
不  没这个必要了
No. That won't be necessary.
亨利是我儿子
Henry is my son.
对亨利来说最好的
The best thing for Henry is to stay with a mother
是留在永不抛弃他的妈妈身边
who will never let go of him,
再也不会
ever again.
恐怕出了点意外
I'm afraid there's been a hiccup.
你们要重新等待了
You'll have to go back on the waiting list.
那位妈妈改主意了
The mother changed her mind.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们失去他了吗
We... Lost him?
是的  但你们可以重新排队
Yes, but I can put you back on the list.
潘会不高兴的
Pan will not be pleased.
我们不会放弃的
Which is why we don't give up.
我们会得到那孩子
We will get that child.
动不了吗
Having trouble moving?
鉴于是这儿  意料之中
Not surprised, given where you are.
你们的悔意会加速你们的死亡
You see, what's hastening your demise is your regret.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
在这发生了对我很重要的事
This tree is the site of a very important event for me.
我在这抛弃了我儿子
I abandoned my boy here.
你还有儿子
You have a son?
我比看上去大多了
I'm older than I look.
如果你有孩子  你肯定也后悔抛弃他
If you have a child, you must regret losing him, too.
但我不后悔
But I don't.
事实上  正好相反
Quite the opposite, actually.
你看  我把他装盒子里了
See, I have him all boxed up,
这样我就不会再失去他
so I don't lose him again.
朗普斯金是你儿子吗
Rumplestiltskin is your son?
是的
That he is.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
你...
You're...
比他年轻吗  其实不是
Younger than him? Not really.
就像你和你女儿
Just like you and your daughter.
你在说谎
You're a fraud.
你的魔力很弱了
Your magic is weakened.
你甚至伤不了我们
You can't even hurt us,
更别提抓朗普斯金了
let alone Rumplestiltskin.
你说得对
You're right.
但这是我来这的原因
But that's why I'm here.
这棵树会保护我  直到我恢复魔力
This tree will protect me until my power is restored.
然后...
And then...
然后我就去找点乐子
Well, then I get to have some real fun.
我再也不用惦记我的孩子了
And I'll have to ever worry about my child again.
我们马上会达成一致的
Something else we will all soon have in common.
一定有别的办法
There has to be another way.
没有  你们再也找不到我
No, you're not going to get to me.
这棵树攻击每个来这的人
See, this tree attacks the regret inside
内心的悔意  而你呢
anyone who comes here. And you?
你心里有不少
You've got plenty.
我后悔之前有机会时
I regret not taking a better shot at you
没能把握好
when I had a chance.
这可不是全部  不是吗  救世主
Well, that's not all, is it, savior?
不是
No.
你儿子的心在我身体里
I have your son's heart inside me.
我能感到你一次又一次
I can feel just how much you let him down
让他有多失望
time and time again.
别再这么说她了
Leave her alone.
也许是吧
Perhaps I should.
毕竟她哪有机会当个好妈妈
After all, what chance did she have at being a good mother?
看看你给她竖的榜样
Look at the example you've set,
抛弃她28年
abandoning her for 28 years.
你说够了吗
Are you finished?
皇后的遗言
Last words from the queen.
可能是有最多后悔人的
Perhaps a deathbed confession
临终独白
from the one who has the most to regret of all.
确实  不过有个问题
Yeah, there's one problem with that.
我的确下了摧毁所有人的诅咒
I did cast a curse that devastated an entire population.
我虐待过别人  也杀过人
I have tortured and murdered.
我做过很多坏事
I've done some terrible things.
我应该被后悔掩埋  但是...
I should be overflowing with regret, but...
我没有
I'm not.
因为这让我想起我儿子
Because it got me my son.
现在...
Now...
我们去救亨利
let's go save Henry.
亨利  他在哪
Henry?! Where is he?
他在这
He's over here!
坚持住  亨利
hold on, Henry.
亨利
Henry?
我们来晚了吗
Are we too late?
亨利
Henry?
亲爱的
Honey!
别着急  小家伙
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Take it easy, buddy.
对不起  我
I'm sorry. I...
我只是想要拯救魔法
I wanted to save magic.
没事  没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
我想做个英雄
I-I wanted to be a hero.
还有很多足够多的时间让你做个英雄呢
There's plenty of time for that.
现在该好好休息
And now it's time to rest.
欢迎回来  年轻人
welcome back, young sir.
把最好的都给我们的贵宾
Only the best for our guest of honor,
你们说呢  去船长室
don't you think? Captain's quarters.
来吧  我来带你去安顿下来
Come on. I'll tuck you in.
瑞金娜  我真的很高兴
Regina, I'm just so pleased.
我得承认  我之前很担心
I'll admit, I was concerned.
我很高兴一切都能顺利解决
And I'm just so glad the way things worked out.
还有一个问题  和普医生
There's just one problem, Dr. Hopper.
我担心
I'm afraid...
不  我
No, I'm...
害怕
dreading...
亨利的生母有一天会突然醒悟
that Henry's birth mother will wake up one day
后悔遗弃他
full of regret over leaving him,
然后来到这里带走他
and come here to take him back.
不是保密收养吗
Wasn't it a closed adoption?
你们两人的信息对彼此
I mean, you're both perfectly anonymous
都是完全保密的  不是吗
to each other, right?
是的  但是我担心的是比法律
Yes, but I'm worried about something bigger
更强大的东西
than the law is at play.
命运
Fate.
天命
Destiny.
在我看来  你已经决定了自己的命运
It seems to me like you've made your own destiny.
但是还是有人
But there's still someone out there
能够摧毁这一切
who can destroy it.
瑞金娜  如果你一直担心未来
Regina, if you keep worrying about the future,
你就无法享受现在
you'll never enjoy the present.
这个孩子给你带来了
This child has brought something to you--
爱
Love.
好好享受它  好好享受作为一个母亲
Revel in that. Revel in being a mother.
谢谢你  父亲
Thank you, father.
很久以前  有一个皇后
Once upon a time, there was a queen,
她施了一个美好的咒语
and she cast a glorious curse,
那个咒语给了她一切她想要的
that gave her everything she wanted...
至少她是这么认为的
Or so she thought.
当她了解到  复仇还不够时
She despaired when she learned that...
她绝望了
revenge was not enough.
她很寂寞
She was lonely.
所以她四处搜寻  找到了一个小男孩
And so she searched the land for a little boy
来做她的王子
to be her prince.
然后
And then...
她找到了他
She found him.
尽管他们快乐地生活在一起
And though they lived happily,
但这并能不永久
it was not ever after.
外面还潜伏着邪恶
There was still an evil out there lurking.
皇后担心她得小王子的安全
The queen was worried for her prince's safety.
她知道她可以战胜
While she knew she could vanquish
对他的一切威胁
any threat to the boy,
她也知道她不能忧心忡忡地抚养他
she also knew she couldn't raise him worrying.
不
No.
她需要把她自己的麻烦搁置在一边
She needed to put her own troubles aside,
把孩子放在优先的地位
and put her child first.
因此
And so...
皇后制成了
The queen procured
一种古老的遗忘药剂
an ancient potion of forgetting.
没事的
Oh, it's all right.
如果皇后喝下了药剂
If the queen drinks the potion,
她也不会忘记她的孩子
she won't forget her child.
她只会忘了自己的担忧
She'll only forget her worries...
她的麻烦
her troubles...
她的恐惧
her fears.
一旦这些都被遗忘
And with those gone...
她  和她的王子就能够
she... and her prince can indeed
从此
finally live
幸福地生活在一起
happily ever after.
你好  亨利
Hello, Henry.
我们今天要做什么呢
What shall we do today?
我了解那表情
Oh, I know that look.
那是打了五小时电游之后吃了太多匹萨的表情
That's five hours of Space Paranoids and too much pizza.
匹萨很好吃
Pizza's good.
有点刺痛
It stings.
这是干什么
What's that for?
一个咒语
A spell,
这样就再也没人能够
so no one can ever take your heart
拿走你的心脏了
ever again.
谢谢  妈妈
Thanks, mom.
我们很快就会到家了  我的小王子
We'll be home soon, my little prince.
抱歉不得不这样  亨利
I'm sorry it had to come to this, Henry.
小比
Bae.
爸爸
Papa.
-亨利在哪  -他很安全  很安全
- Where's Henry? - He's safe. He's safe.
我就说我不会伤害他的
I told you I wasn't gonna hurt the boy.
我知道  对不起  我
I know. I'm sorry. I...
你为什么没告诉我潘是你的父亲
Why didn't you tell me Pan was your father?
因为我不想让你知道
Because I didn't want you to know
我和他一样是个糟糕的父亲
that I was as bad a father as he was.
因为我和他  我们都一样
Because we're both the same, me and him,
因为我们都抛弃了自己的儿子
because we both abandoned our sons.
不  你不一样
No, you're not the same.
你为了我回来了  爸爸
You came back for me, papa.
他回来了
He's back.
-那就意味着  -他可以治愈我
- That means... - He can cure me.
我们就能回家了
We can go home...
一家人一起
A family.
怎么了
What's wrong?
干嘛  你在干什么
What? What are you doing?
我想要你的心脏  亨利
I wanted your heart, Henry,
但是你妈妈从我这里夺走了它
but your mother took it away from me
放任我死去
and left me for dead.
这是她的错
Her mistake.
真聪明
Oh, how clever.
你在干什么
Ow! What are you doing?
血魔法两边都有效
Blood magic works both ways...
父亲
Father.
不
No!
亨利  亨利
Henry? Henry!
不
Oh, no.
亨利
Henry!
没事
it's okay.
我没事
I'm okay.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
他是个坚强的孩子  瑞金娜
He's a strong boy, Regina.
你把他抚养得很好
You raised him well.
走  来这边
Go. Over here.
准备好了吗  瑞金娜
Ready, Regina?
你觉得这能飞
You think it'll fly?
没有其他选择了
It has no choice.
让我们离开该死的梦幻岛吧
Then let's get the hell out of Neverland.
如您所愿  女士
As you wish, m'lady.
水手长  起锚
Bosun, weigh anchor!
在我们第一次降落在这个岛上时
You know, when we first landed on this island,
你说我们需要一起努力
you said we'd all need to work together.
我只是尝试一切可能
I was just trying anything.
老实说  我之前觉得不可能
Well, to be honest, I didn't think it was possible.
我不相信英雄  坏人  海盗
That a hero, a villain, a pirate...
可以都团结起来 但是我们做到了
that we could all be united, but we were
就因为这拼图中最重要的一块
because of the most important piece of the puzzle--
一个领导者
a leader.
我很高兴我们能够一起努力
I'm just glad that we were all able to work together
把亨利带回家
and get Henry home.
把所有人都带回家
Get all of us home.
比待在笼子里强多了  是吧
Better than being in a cage, isn't it?
我们真的自由了吗
Are we really free?
是的  温迪
Yes, Wendy.
很快你就能见到你的弟弟们了
Soon, you'll see your brothers.
我有东西给你
I have something for you.
我一直都保存着
I've saved it all this time.
我可能永远也用不到  但是
I could never use it, but...
也许你可以
maybe you can.
这是精灵尘
It's pixie dust.
这是树顶最后一朵花的最后一点精灵尘了
It's the last bit from the last flower in the treetops.
-它是惰性的  -我不能让它起作用
- It's inert-- - I can't make it work.
我没有魔法了
I've got no magic.
从我失去翅膀时就没有了
Not since I lost my wings.
你会想到办法的
You'll figure it out.
我相信你  小叮当
I believe in you, Tink.
你还好吗  你不是该好好休息吗
You feelin' okay? Shouldn't you be resting?
你要是想吃东西我可以给你拿一些来
I could bring you some food if you're feelin' up for it.
我现在感觉好多了
I'm feeling much better now.
-我觉得新鲜空气对我更好  -好吧
- I think the fresh air is good for me. - Okay.
亨利
Henry...
我知道我们还没什么机会
I know we haven't had much of a chance
成为一家人  暂时没有
to be a family. Not yet.
只是  我想让你知道你现在有爸爸了
Just, I want you to know that you have a dad now.
从今往后一直都有
Now and for forever.
我永远都不会离开你的  小家伙
I'll never leave you, okay, buddy?
很高兴你救回了你的儿子  瑞金娜
I'm glad you got your son back, Regina.
看来巫后终究
Seems the evil queen
是能爱上一个人的
was able to love someone after all.
是的  看来是这样的
Yes, it seems.
看来你是对的
It seems you were right.
我知道你内心还有善
I knew you still had some good in you.
匀? 你还有魔法
Apparently, you still have some magic in you.
发生
What--
发生了什么
What happened?
要我说  我只会说有那么一瞬间
Well, if I had to guess, I'd say for a moment there,
你坚信不疑
you believed.
走开  小孩
Go away, boy.
不饿
Not hungry.
我是来谢你的
But I came to thank you.
不管其他叛徒做了什么
No matter what those other traitors do,
我都支持潘
I'm on Pan's side.
-而潘  -永不失败
- And Pan-- - Never fails.
什么
What?
你听到了
You heard me.
彼得·潘永不失败
Peter Pan never fails.
不能被阻止
He can't be stopped.
即使他们都认为他被打败了
Even when they think he's defeated,
他们都认为他们赢了
when they think they've won,
他找到了办法
he finds a way.
你觉得你不安全
So you think you're not safe?
不  我非常安全
Oh, no, I'm perfectly safe.
在我们的斗争中  我的命运被封闭了
During our struggle, my fate was sealed.
有麻烦的那个
The one who's in trouble...
是亨利
is Henry.
但你是亨利
But you're Henry.
不再是了
Not anymore.
你们
You...
你们互换了
You switched.
你确定你不饿吗
You sure you're not hungry?
谢谢你
Thank you...
潘
Pan.
现在
Now...
开始游戏吧
Let's play.
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译 肉松   阿噻   茶炒栗子   蓬蓬裙木瓜   米苏
时间轴 冰蓝   木讷   子衿   后期 、青衣
校对 米苏   总监 wdjmhs